I cast the orb unto the Earth.
（観察者）
私は球(きゅう)を この地上へ投げ入れた
Its function is to gather information.
それは情報を収集するために
機能する
Light.
光 ニオイ
Scents.
Sounds.
音 喜び
Happiness.
Sadness.
悲しみ…
All this information and the
stimulation it brings with it
多種多様な情報と その刺激により
allows the orb to change into many forms.
さまざまな姿に
変化できるようになるのだ
It took on the appearance of the boy
それは少年に姿を変え
and set off.
旅立った
A girl of the Ninannah region, March.
ニナンナの少女マーチ
She was chosen to be sacrificed to Oniguma...
彼女はオニグマの
いけにえに選ばれたが
But she fled on her way to the ritual.
儀式に向かう途中 逃走した
And from March's actions,
そしてマーチの行動によって
it receives further stimulation.
それは新たな刺激を獲得する
"Thank you."
（マーチ）
“あ… り… が… と… う”
Thank you.
“ありがとう”
The journey of the orb,
（観察者）刺激に満ちた
この世界をさまよう それの旅は
traveling through this stimulation-rich world,
had only just begun.
まだ始まったばかりである
Sheesh...
もう！　マーチは
あんたのママじゃないんだからね！
I'm not your mommy, you know!
♪～
～♪
Put your hands out.
（マーチ）手を出して
ヘヘッ
Like this.
こうするの
Here you go.
はい どうぞ
ハァ… 本当に子供ね
You're such a child.
And you don't even have ink on your face.
お顔に墨もないのに
By the way, where did you come from?
そういえば あんた
どこから来たの？
Not Ninannah, right? And you don't
look like you're from Yanome...
ニナンナじゃないもんね
ヤノメっぽくもないし…
Are you one of the legendary Doki people?
ひょっとして伝説のドキ人？
Oh, right.
そうだ！
あんたに名前つけてあげる
I need to give you a name.
Let's see...
えーと 不死身だから
フジミちゃん
You're immortal, so Fujimi-chan.
うーん… フジちゃん？
Fuji-chan?
Oh! How about Fushi-chan?
あ！　フシちゃんなんて
どうかしら？
Lame?
ダサい？
How about Fu-chan, then?
じゃあ フーちゃんは？
Fu-chan!
フーちゃん！　エヘヘ…
A Small Evolution
（従者Ｂ）あー
I'm so bored, I'm about to fall asleep.
ヒマすぎて寝ちまいそうだ
They sure are taking their time.
（従者Ｄ）あいつら 遅(おせ)えよな
（従者Ｂのいびき）
（パロナ）くっ
（うなり声）
う…
（従者Ｄ）ん？
あ…
（足音）
What is that?
（従者Ｂ）ん… 何だ？
（足音）
ハッ
（従者Ｄ）ああ…
（従者Ｂ）ううっ
（オニグマの咆哮(ほうこう)）
（うなり声）
（従者Ｂ）うわっ
（従者Ｄ）えいっ… えいっ…
んん… くっ
ああ！
Run!
（従者Ｄ）逃げろ！　く…
うわっ… うっ うう…
ギャアアア！
（パロナ）あ…
（従者Ｂ）う… あ… うわああ…
（うなり声）
ハッ
（咆哮）
あ！　うう…
うっ
ハッ
（荒い息遣い）
うわっ
く…
ああ！
ハッ
March!
マーチ…
あ！
There you are, March-san.
（ハヤセ）
見つけましたよ マーチさん
ああ…
（パロナ）うっ あ…
あっ う…
うあっ
プハッ！　ハァ ハァ ハァ…
うう… マーチ…
March...
I'm coming to save you.
今 助けに行くからな！
Fu-chan!
（マーチ）フーちゃん ママ行くね
Mommy's going now.
Just kidding.
なんちゃって…
Thank you!
ありがと！
Most animals cannot choose
their own environments.
（観察者）たいていの動物は
自分がいる環境を選べない
Therefore, in order to adapt,
よって その場に適応するために
they need to change themselves.
自らを変化させる必要がある
For humans, especially,
such changes are preceded
とりわけ人間にとって
変化の兆しとなるのが感情なのだ
by emotion.
（パロナ）ふっ
（荒い息遣い）
March...
（パロナ）マーチ どこだ？
どこに行った！
Where are you?
Where have you gone?
（パロナ）ハッ
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Hey...
あの… 小さい… 女の子
見ませんでしたか？
Have you seen a little girl?
ハァハァ… 髪の長い…
She has long hair...
あっ あ…
Where are you going?
どこへ？
Where...
どこへ…
ん？
あっ
Those flags...
あれは…
Now, eat this.
（ハヤセ）
さあ これを食べてください
（マーチ）ん？
んん…
What is this? It tastes weird.
何これ？　ヘンな味…
All girls who are to be offered must eat that.
（ハヤセ）ささげ物の女の子は
みんな これを食べるんですよ
Be sure to eat the whole thing.
全部 食べてくださいね
ふーん
By the way, March-san...
そういえばマーチさん
Who was that man who was with you earlier?
先ほど一緒にいた
あの人物は何者ですか？
He didn't seem to be of
either Yanome or Ninannah.
ヤノメでもニナンナでも
なさそうでしたが…
んん…
He said he's a traveler.
旅人だって
He just happened to be there.
たまたま あそこにいたの
You liar!
（従者Ａ）
う… ウソをつくんじゃねえ
Hayase!
（従者Ｃ）ハヤセ！　あいつが昨日
俺らが見たヤバいヤツっす！
He's the monster we saw yesterday!
He's not of this world!
（従者Ａ）この世のモンじゃない
バケモンっすよ
He's a monster!
Huh?
E-Everyone!
はあ？
（従者Ｂ）い… いた！
（４人）ハッ
Everyone!
（従者Ｂ）みんな！
Hey, weren't you on guard duty?
（従者Ｅ）おい 見張りはどうした
なぜ ここへ？
Why are you here?
Don't come any farther!
（従者Ｂ）この先はダメです
襲撃されて１人 失いました
We were attacked! We lost one man!
Attacked?
Yeah!
襲撃？
It was a bear!
（従者Ｂ）ええ クマです！
A bear?
（従者Ｅ）クマだと？
The spines on its body...
（従者Ｂ）あの体のトゲ…
きっとオニグマ様だ！
It must have been Oniguma-sama!
Come on, Oniguma-sama is just a legend.
（従者Ｅ）
おい オニグマ様は伝説だろ？
Are you sure it wasn't an
ordinary bear you saw?
お前が見たのは
普通のクマだったんじゃないのか？
No!
（従者Ｂ）違う！　あれは
ただのクマじゃねえ！
That was no ordinary bear!
All right.
仕方ない 迂回(うかい)して
直接 祭壇へ行こう
Let's go around it and head
straight to the altar.
Are you serious?!
（従者たち）ええ？
（従者Ａ）本気ですか？
Between that monster and that bear...
（従者Ｃ）あのバケモノといい
クマといい 普通じゃない！
Something's not right!
Let's go back to the village!
村に帰りましょうよ
We will not.
（ハヤセ）ダメだ
（従者たち）あ… くっ
（マーチ）んっ
ハァ…
あ…
（寝息）
Let's go.
行くぞ
I won't become a grown-up
I chose so, by myself
"That's a commendable choice, March-san"
This is for the best
She's sound asleep.
（従者Ｅ）ちゃんと眠ってます
It's done.
（従者Ａ）完了です
Let's go.
帰ろう
This mission was exhausting.
今回の任務は疲れた
We need to report the death to Yanome.
死者が出たことも
ヤノメに報告せねば
（森に響く何かの音）
（近づいてくる音）
What is that sound?
（従者Ｅ）何だ この音？
That's...
（従者Ａ）あれは…
（咆哮）
（従者Ａ）ああ…
It can't be!
（従者Ｅ）まさか！
Oniguma-sama!
オニグマ様… 本当にいたとは…
It really exists...
ハッ
March!
マーチ！
Hey, you!
（従者Ａ）あ！　お前…
Wait.
待て いいじゃないか
Let her be.
It can have twice the food.
エサが２つになるだけだ
（吠(ほ)え声）
ハッ
ああ…
く… ううっ
It's so tight...
固っ！
（荒い息遣い）
う… 起きろ！
Wake up!
March!
マーチ！
There's no reason...
しきたりなんて…
to follow these old customs!
守る必要ない！
If you want to become a grown-up,
that's your decision to make!
自分で大人になることを
選んでいいんだ！
ハッ
Let's go.
行きましょう
Close the gate.
門を閉めてください
（従者Ａ）ん？
（従者Ｅ）ん？
（ハヤセ）あ…
ハッ
（パロナ）ああ…
（オニグマのうなり声）
（ハヤセ）あっ
It ate him.
（従者Ｅ）食われた
No.
（ハヤセ）いや 待て… あいつ…
Wait...
He's still trying to do something.
まだ… 何かしようと
（一同）ああ！
あ…
（オオカミのうなり声）
ハッ
（オニグマの吠え声）
（オニグマのうめき声）
（オオカミ）キャン…
（うなり声）
（咆哮）
（オニグマのうめき声）
What is happening?
（ハヤセ）何だ… あれは？
Is it an act of the gods?
神の御業(みわざ)か？
March!
（パロナ）マーチ… マーチ！
マーチ！
あ…
ん？
あっ マーチ！
March!
Sissy...
ねーね…
What happened?
何があったの？
（パロナ）あ…
ハッ くっ
Listen to me.
聞きなさい
We will report that
儀式は成功し マーチさんは
死んだことにしてあげます
the ritual was a success and March-san died.
What?
え？
You understand what this means.
（ハヤセ）
どういうことか分かりますね？
（パロナ）うっ
The two of you will die, or you
will come to our land alive.
ここで２人で死ぬか
生きて我らの国へ行くか
決めなさい
Choose.
（パロナ）ハッ
ん？
March.
マーチ… 行こう！
Let's go.
Let's live!
生きよう！
We're taking them back to Yanome.
ヤノメに持ち帰るぞ すべてを
All of them.
All of them?
（従者Ｅ）すべて？
（マーチ）フフッ
The kids, the bear, and...
（ハヤセ）ガキとクマ そして…
that wolf.
あのオオカミも
（従者Ａ）う… わわっ
う… うう！
あっ
（マーチ）あ…
ヘヘッ
What's wrong, puppy?
（オオカミの吠え声）
どうしたの ワンちゃん？
おなか空いたの？
Are you hungry?
No, March!
（オオカミの吠え声）
マーチ ダメだ！
こいつは危険なんだ
That thing's dangerous!
（２人）あ…
He's eating it.
食べた
（ゲップの音）
（２人）ん？
Thank you.
（オオカミ）あ… りがとオ
♪～
～♪
Preview
Parona and March escape death,
captured by Hayase.
（観察者）
ハヤセのとらわれの身となり
死をまぬがれたパロナとマーチ
In the vibrant city of Yanome,
they experience the joys of living.
華やかなヤノメの街で
生きる喜びを謳歌(おうか)する
But Hayase's plots to unravel immortality
しかし 不死身のフシをめぐる
ハヤセの策略が
threaten to ensnare the two once again.
彼らを再び陥れようとしていた
A Large Vessel